glu.com 2012-12-13

# Privacy Policy

**Glu Mobile Inc. Privacy Policy**

**Last updated:   May_21, 2012**

**Table of contents**

I.         Introduction

II.        What is Personal Information

III.       When We Collect Information 

IV.      How We Collect Information

V.       How We Use Personal Information

VI.      Sharing Your Information

VII.     Your Messaging Options

VIII.     International Operations and Transfers

IX.       Privacy Policies of Linked Sites and Advertisers

X.       Security of Your Information

XI.       Changes to Our Privacy Policy

XII.      California Residents: Your California Privacy Rights

XIII.     A Special Note about Children

XIV.    How To Review and Correct Your Information

XV.     How to Contact us.

**I.           Introduction**

Glu Mobile Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “Glu,” “we,” “our,” or “us”) respect the privacy rights of our customers and online visitors and recognize the importance of protecting the information collected about you. We have created this Privacy Policy, to provide you with information regarding how we or third parties collect, store and use the information you provide through (i) our web sites, including without limitation [www.glugames.com](http://www.glugames.com/), [www.glu.com](http://www.glu.com/), [games.glu.com](http://games.glu.com/), m.glu.com and Glu’s Glu Games Network, (ii) third party social networking services such as Facebook, Google+, or Twitter (each, an “SNS”) including Glu's fan pages on these SNSs (items (i) and (ii) collectively the “Sites”), and (iii) through our mobile applications, our web-based applications that we manage and through other means such as Glu newsletters, Glu’s other advertising directed at you and Glu sweepstakes and contests (the items listed in clauses (i) through (iii) are collectively referred to in this Privacy Policy as the "Services"). 

Please note that except as otherwise described herein this Privacy Policy does not apply to (1) information collected and stored by or through services and websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which our Sites or Services may link or are incorporated in the Services, (2) information collected and stored by web-based applications that are based on our mobile applications but are published by third parties, (3) information collected and stored by mobile applications that we distribute on behalf of third parties which mobile applications are hosted by such third parties or (4) on-line submission of resumes, employment applications and the like.

If you have any questions, complaints, or comments regarding our Privacy Policy, please contact our [Privacy Policy Administrator](mailto:privacy@glu.com). You may also contact our Privacy Policy Administrator by writing to: Privacy Policy Administrator, Glu Mobile Inc., 45 Fremont Street, Suite 2800, San Francisco, CA 94105-2209.

By using the Sites or the Services, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Sites or the Services.

**II.          What is Personal Information?**

When we use the term "personal information" in this Privacy Policy, we are referring to (1) information that specifically identifies an individual (such as an individual's first and last name, mailing address, telephone number, account or user name, e-mail address or other account number), (2) information about that individual or such individual's activities or preferences when such information is directly linked to personally identifying information, and (3) information that may be used to contact you on-line or off-line.  “Personal information” might include your unique device or user identifier when the identifier is combined with your personal information.  Personal information does not include "aggregate information," which is data we gather and use to create aggregate statistics about our customers and visitors and enhance our Services and our Sites, as well as information regarding sales, Services usage, traffic patterns, and related web site information from which any personal information has been removed or has not been associated with an individual. Aggregate information may include demographic information, such as gender, age, city or town of residence, your unique device or user identifier (when not collected with or tied to or matched with your personal information), information about your hardware, software, platform, Internet IP address and connection, and information about your on-line activity. 

**III.         When we collect Information **

We may collect your personal information, as described above, during (1) your download and your use of our mobile applications and our web-based applications that we manage, (2) contests and sweepstakes (registration and claiming a prize), (3) customer support or technical service requests, (4) registration or log-in for games, games subscriptions, the Sites (Glu Games Network, for example), or special game-specific event participation, (5) your communications with other registered members on the Sites or through the Services, (6) registration for newsletter subscriptions, promotional materials, marketing surveys, email campaigns and other alerts, (7) your placement of an order for the Services, products or subscriptions from us, and (8) your request for services from third party service providers on the Sites or the Services (for example, your response to incented third-party advertisements).  Information collected will vary depending upon your activity. Prize winners of contests or sweepstakes may also have to provide their Social Security Numbers for tax purposes. 

You can avoid most data collection if you continuously play our games in the off-line mode by turning off your device’s wi-fi connection or changing other settings on your device; however, if you do so, your operation of the game will be limited.  For example, you will not be able to conduct in-app purchases in the off-line mode.

**When You Use an SNS, a Third Party Service or Certain Distributors** ****

In addition to the occasions listed above, when you (1) use an SNS or a third party gaming-related service, such as OpenFeint, Game Spy or Apple’s iTunes GameCenter (each a “Third Party Service”) to log into one of our mobile or web-based applications that we manage or (2) acquire one of our mobile applications through certain game distributors such as the Amazon AppStore or the Google Play store, you may be allowing Glu to access certain personal information from your profile you created for that SNS, Third Party Service or distributor. The categories of information you allow Glu to access varies by game and SNS platform, Third Party Service or distributor.  The level of details about you that Glu may access is generally controlled by the privacy settings you establish at the SNS, Third Party Service or distributor and by the respective privacy policies of the SNS, Third Party Service or distributor with regard to their abilities to provide personal information to third parties such as Glu.  You can control and find out more about these settings at the respective site of the SNS, Third Party Service or distributor you use in connection with our mobile applications and web-based applications that we manage.  For example, Glu may access and store some or all of the following information, as allowed by you, an SNS, Third Party Service or distributor and your privacy settings: your first and last name, your profile picture or its URL, your device or user identifier, which is linked to publicly available information such as name and profile photo, your telephone number, the device or user identifier for your friends that are also connected to our Services, the login e-mail address you provided to that SNS, Third Party Service or distributor when you registered, your location and that of your access device(s), your gender, your date of birth and the contents of any messages you may post while on the Sites, or using an SNS, Third Party Service or distributor.

By logging in to play a Glu game through an SNS or a Third Party Service or by downloading an application from certain distributors, you are authorizing Glu to collect, store, and use in accordance with this Privacy Policy any and all information that you agreed the SNS, Third Party Service could share with Glu. Your agreement takes place when you use an SNS or a Third Party Service to log in to or download one of our applications or otherwise in connection with playing our games. 

**When You Use a Mobile Device or Personal Computer** ****

When you download and when you play Glu games on your mobile telephone or other mobile device or on a personal computer, we collect your in-game actions, your unique device or user identifier  and country in which the telephone or device is registered or located, and may collect your telephone number, and other information you choose to provide, such as user name, or e-mail address.  When you use our mobile or web-based applications, we also collect information about your mobile device type, your IP address, browser type and operating system.  For Android games subscriptions for Glu’s freemium games (including subscriptions through Google Play and the Amazon App Store, we require that you provide us with your email address and require your consent to use your email address to contact you before you will be allowed to download a game.  For example, see the Google permissions associated with a Glu game available on Google Play.  You have the option to use your Facebook information in order to use our Glu Games Network application and site; alternatively you may create a user name and password. We use this information in connection with providing our mobile and web-based applications, such as to authenticate you and to communicate with you regarding our services by e-mail, push notification, SMS, text message or other electronic means to your mobile device.

When you respond to advertising in our applications, we and our advertising and analytics vendors and partners will be collecting your responses, clicks and other reactions to the ads, as well as information about your use of the application in which the advertising appears.  In some cases, we will associate this information with your unique device or user identifier for our internal use.  Our vendors and partners may also collect some or all of this game and application related activity information; their usage of your information is subject to their respective privacy policies. 

**When You Post in On-line Forums or Subscribe to Glu Services**

Should you choose to participate in on-line discussions or leave comments on our Sites' forums or message boards or an SNS fan page, any information you provide in such forums is public information, posted at your own risk, and there is no expectation of privacy or confidentiality there. Information you provide in these forums is **_not_** subject to this Privacy Policy.

If you subscribe to a Glu e-mail newsletter or to our Services, request support, send us an email, or otherwise contact us through the Sites or the Services, we collect the personal information that you supply in such communication. We use such information to fulfill and contact you regarding your request and for other purposes as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**IV.        How We Collect Information**

We may collect information about you in any one or more of the following ways:

**In-Game** **Automatic Processes**

As stated above, we collect your personal and aggregate information when you visit the Sites or use the Services. 

While you use our mobile or web-based applications or visit our Sites, your mobile device or personal computer transmits information about your activities and actions in the application, as well as information you enter while using the application, to our servers. 

In some instances we require your email address and require your consent to use your email address to contact you before you will be allowed to download a game or use our Glu Games Network application and site; where you do not provide that personal information, you may not be able to access certain areas or utilize functions that require registration. 

In and through our applications, we and service providers acting on our behalf, such as Google AdMob, Flurry, PlayHaven (Medium Entertainment Inc.), Tapjoy, ChartBoost, and Google’s and other companies’ various analytics services and tools, use server log files and tracking technologies to collect and analyze certain types of your technical information, including your unique device identifier, IP addresses, browser types, browser language, referring and exit pages, and URLs, platform type, the number of clicks, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed and the order of those pages, the amount of time spent on particular games, apps, pages, your in-game progress, and the date and time of activity on our websites or games, and other similar information. In some cases when this information is shared with us by our service providers, we will associate this information with your unique device or user identifier for our internal use. 

Our third party service providers use standard data collection methodologies that might include tags and cookies that are sent to your device or personal computer through our games; we collect and track your usage information as it relates to our mobile and web-based games and the websites you visit.  The mobile browser version of the Glu Games Network uses a cookie to remember the location of your profile picture for display.  A cookie is a small text file recorded on your computer’s hard drive and/or on your mobile device that identifies you as a unique user and contains certain information about your particular login session and/or your use of the Service.  You can set your personal computer’s and device’s web browser to warn you about attempts to place cookies on your computer and device, or limit the type of cookies you allow.

If you respond to an in-game offer or advertisement, our marketing and advertising services providers include tracking mechanisms that can determine whether a certain page was visited or whether an email was opened.  Please note that companies delivering advertisements in our games or on our Sites may also use cookies or other technologies, and those practices are subject to their own privacy policies.  In addition, if any application includes advertising with location-based offers or services, your clicks on ads and location may be collected through and by a Third Party Service’s SDK (software development kit) while using such feature. 

To minimize the collection of your data and behavior by our marketing and advertising partners, do not respond to any advertisements or purchase the ad-free versions of our games, if available.

When you play one of our games, Glu collects and stores certain profile information that you provide directly to us or through the SNS or other third party distributor that is offering our game(s).  To provide a richer game play and social experience, we also collect information about your play and interaction with other players and the Services.  The bulk of this information is collected and stored through the use of web logs, which are files on our web servers that record actions taken on our games and websites.  A copy is stored on your device.

**Through** **Facebook and Other Log-In Methods**

If you use one of our applications in conjunction with Facebook (or another SNS) or a Third Party Service account whether you connect from our application or you connect from the SNS, you will be providing us with basic account or profile information (i.e., user ID, name, email, gender, birthday, current city, profile picture URL and the user IDs of your friends who have also connected with our applications), but limited by your privacy settings with the SNS or Third Party Service.  We retain this information for as long as you are logged in via Facebook or similar SNS or Third-Party Service log-in method. 

**Through Your Use of Communications Features**

You may be able to take part in certain activities on our Sites or games that give you the opportunity to communicate or share information not just with Glu, but also with other users of our Services.  These include: participating in player forums and message boards, playing our games in multi-player mode (where this feature is available for a game), posting public comments to other users' profiles or gameboards, sending private messages or invitations to other users, either directly on our websites or to their e-mail accounts, chatting with other users, and/or posting photos. We may record and store archives of these communications on Glu's servers to protect the safety and well being of our users and Glu's rights and property in connection with the Services.  **_In using the Sites and the Services, you acknowledge and consent to the recording and storage of such communications for these purposes._**   Communications you make on third party sites, including SNSs (for example, Facebook or GameCenter) are subject to their privacy policies.  

**Through Other Sources**

We may collect or receive information from other sources including (i) other Glu users who choose to upload their email contacts, and (ii) third party information providers.  This information will be used to supplement your profile, primarily to help you and your friends connect. It will be combined with other information we collect for our internal purposes.

**v.         How We Use Personal Information**

We use information about your computer and mobile device, such as the IP addresses of your devices, unique device or user identifier, browser type and operating system version, to contact you, complete your transactions (as needed), administer your inquiries and requests for technical support, and provide more personalized Services (i.e., to receive updates about us, the mobile game or to receive in-game items).  We use personal and aggregate information to learn about and resolve problems with our applications, to diagnose problems with our server, to administer our Sites, to provide and improve our Sites and Services and to develop new product and services.  Your information may also be used to formulate broad demographic information that does not personally identify you.

When you access our Sites or the Services or play our games, we collect and share certain technical aggregate information in order to (i) analyze the usage of our Sites and Services which allows us to improve our Sites and Service, (ii) provide a more personalized experience and (iii) assist with the management of advertising that may appear in our mobile applications.

We use your unique device or user identifier to prevent fraudulent game play or other actions and to remember your in-game settings for features like sound level and tracking your progress on certain in-game tasks. 

In addition to any of the specific uses mentioned above, we may use the personal information we collect (a) to contact you about your use of the Sites or the Services, such as for administrative purposes; (b) for the purpose for which it was provided, such as to provide our products and Services; (c) to notify you about important changes to our policies, the Sites or the Services; (d) to alert you regarding new and existing Glu features, products, services, promotions and events that we think you may find interesting and for other internal marketing and promotional purposes if you opt-in or request this type of communication from us; and (e) to request feedback regarding our Sites and Services and to develop new products and services. 

**Consumer Data**

We may use survey responses to marketing surveys to select and direct advertising for Services that are more likely to be of interest to you. Participation in marketing surveys is entirely optional. We may share aggregate consumer data (which does not contain personal information) with our advertising and marketing companies. However, we do not disclose your personal information to our advertisers without your consent, and we do not use, share or disclose such personal information other than as set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

We may use your personal information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can consistently improve our Sites and Services to better meet your needs.

**Third-Party Advertising**

We may serve ads on our Sites and Services through the use of third-party advertising vendors. The third-party advertising technology (APIs and/or SDKs) uses information derived from your activity within our applications,  your visits to the Glu games and to the SNSs and Third Party Services you use, as described above, to target advertising within our Sites or Glu games. These service providers may also collect some or all of the technical information and your user or device identifier to fulfill incented advertisements, serve advertisements and/or aggregate your information to compile and use such aggregated data for our marketing and analytics purposes; the collection and usage of your information by these service providers is subject to their respective privacy policies.In the course of advertisements being served to you, a unique third-party cookie or cookies may be placed on your computer. Similarly, third-party advertising companies may provide us with pixel tags (also called “clear gifs” or “beacons”) to help manage and optimize our online advertising. Beacons enable us to recognize a browser's cookie when a browser visits the site on which the beacon is located, and to learn which banner ads bring users to a given site.

Whatever the purpose may be, we will only collect information to the extent reasonably necessary to fulfill your requests and our legitimate business objectives.

**vi.        Sharing Your Information**

**Opt-In Provision**

We do not share your personal information with third parties, except as described by this Privacy Policy. However, if we intend to share such information with more third parties, we will ask you to opt-in or consent to sharing your personal information with parties outside of Glu (except to the extent required by law, court order, or as requested by other government or law enforcement authority) when we first collect information about you. In addition, if you do not want us to send you e-mail or postal mail about our products and services, you can choose not to opt-in at the time of registration or information collection; however in some instances you will not be allowed to download or use a Service unless you consent to use your email address to contact you.  If, at a later date, you choose to have your name removed from our mailing list, you can do so by unsubscribing as directed in the newsletter, or by contacting our Privacy Policy Administrator. You may also click the “unsubscribe” link on our email offers and newsletters.

We may disclose or transfer your personal information (a) to our corporate affiliates (for example, to our subsidiaries), (b) to our service providers (for example, marketing, fulfillment, hosting, or payment service providers), but only for their use to provide the requested service to you, or (c) where you provide your express consent to the disclosure. We will require our corporate affiliates and service providers that receive your personal information to limit their use and disclosure of your information to the purposes for which you provided it.

Except as described in this Privacy Policy, we will not share your personal information with third parties unless you have consented to the disclosure or we believe the disclosure is appropriate to: (1) comply with the law or with legal process, (2) protect and defend our rights and property, such as to determine, bill and collect for amounts owed to us or to enforce our Terms of Service, (3) protect our customers or users, including from misuse or unauthorized use of the Sites or our Services, (4) in other circumstances in which Glu believes the Sites or Services are being used in the commission of a crime (including exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction), or (5)when we have a good faith belief that there is an emergency that poses a threat to the safety of you or another person. 

In the event that Glu undergoes a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, we may transfer all of your information, including personal information, to the successor organization in such transition. If material changes to Glu's privacy practices will occur as a result of the business transition, we will notify you and other users of the business transition prior to transferring your personal information.

This policy does not limit or restrict our collection of aggregate information, and we may disclose this information to third parties.

**vii.       Your Sharing and Messaging Options**

**Information We Receive from Third-Party SNS and Distributors** ****

If you play our games at an SNS or download our games from certain distributors, Glu will be able to access and store profile and other personal information about you as described above.  Glu does not control what privacy settings those sites make available to their users, so we refer you to the privacy policies that are posted on those sites to learn what options they make available to their users.  Glu does not offer an "opt out" option for specific fields that are shared by the SNS where you access and play the game(s).

**Opting out of Promotional Communications** ****

You can choose to opt out of receiving additional promotional e-mails from Glu by clicking on the "unsubscribe" link in any such e-mail, or by not checking the box included when we request your email address.  Please note that once we receive your request, it may take an additional period of time for your opt-out to become effective. 

When you install our apps on your mobile device you can choose to receive push notifications.  These notifications can be turned off by modifying your mobile device settings for notifications. Note that if you opt-out of our promotional communications, we may still e-mail or communicate with you from time to time if we need to provide you with information or if we need to request information from you with respect to a transaction initiated by you or for other legitimate non-marketing reasons.

**viiI.      International Operations and Transfers**

Glu is a global organization and the computer systems on which we collect, store and use the information we collect or receive may be based in North America, Asia, Europe, Latin America and elsewhere. Your personal information may be transferred to, used, processed or held by us in these and in other countries, including countries both in and outside the European Union, and used for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy.

As part of our international operations, we may transfer data including personal data to our corporate affiliates from time to time for our legitimate business purposes. For example, Glu Mobile Inc. provides certain services to its corporate affiliates.

Glu stores information about most of its Site visitors and players on servers located in the United States, and Glu’s Affiliate in China stores such information on servers and equipment located in that country.  Personal data collected within Switzerland and the European Economic Area (“EEA”) is transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside of Switzerland and the EEA. The data we hold may also be processed by employees operating outside of Switzerland and the EEA who work for us or one of our Affiliates or for one of our vendors. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, (i) the processing of transactions and (ii) the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data or downloading or playing Glu games, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing of your data.

We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

**ix.         Privacy Policies of Linked Sites and Advertisers**

The Sites and Services may contain links to web sites belonging to third parties not related to Glu that may be of interest to you. When you leave the Sites or the Services, our policies, including this Privacy Policy, no longer govern because Glu cannot control the activities of third parties. Any information you provide to these third parties is subject to their privacy policies, which may differ from ours. Glu is not responsible for the actions of those parties, the content of their web sites, collection or use of information you provide to them or any products or services they may offer. Our link to a third-party web site does not constitute our sponsorship of, or affiliation with, the third party or the third party's web site. We encourage you to review and understand the privacy policies of these third parties before providing personal information to them.

We may employ third party companies and individuals to provide and/or facilitate our Services, to perform tasks, such as sending out newsletters, SMS messages and/or process in-game actions, or to assist us in analyzing how the Sites and Services are being used. These tasks necessarily require that we share your personal information with such third parties. We require that they adhere to this Privacy Policy and protect the confidentiality of your personal information, and they are prohibited from using your personal information for any other purposes without your consent.

**x.          Security of Your Information**

We have put reasonable security measures in place to prevent the loss, misuse, destruction and alteration of information under our control. For user accounts registered directly with Glu, profile information is protected by the password each member uses to access their online account. It is important that you protect and maintain the security of your account and that you immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your account. 

While we take reasonable precautions against possible security breaches of our Sites and our customer databases and records, no website or Internet transmission is completely secure, and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized access, hacking, data loss, or other breaches will never occur. We urge you to take steps to keep your personal information safe (including your account password), and to log out of your account after use.  If you have questions about the security of our Sites, please contact us at privacy@Glu.com.

**xi.         Changes to Our Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Please check this Privacy Policy each time you use the Sites or the Services to ensure you are aware of any changes in our privacy practices. Our Privacy Policy will indicate the date it was last updated. We will notify you of any material changes by posting a revised policy on [glu.com](http://games.glu.com/). Your continued use of the Sites and/or the Services will signify your acceptance of the changes to our Privacy Policy.

**xii.        California residents: your california Privacy Rights**

Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California have the right to request from a business, with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, the identity of any third parties to whom the business has disclosed personal information within the previous calendar year, along with the type of personal information disclosed, for the third parties' direct marketing purposes.

We do not share personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you affirmatively agree to such disclosure by "opting in" to receive information from a third party in connection with a sweepstakes or other promotion. If you do ask us to share your personal information with a third party for its marketing purposes, we will only share information in connection with that specific promotion, as we do not share information with any third party (other than our service providers) on a continual basis.  To prevent disclosure of your personal information for use in direct marketing by a third party, please do not opt in to such use when you provide personal information on one of the Sites.

**xiii.       A Special Note About Children**

We recognize a special obligation to protect personal information obtained from young children, and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from such children. Therefore, no information should be submitted by children 13 years of age or under.  In the event that we learn that we have inadvertently gathered personal information from children under the age of 13, we will take reasonable measures to promptly erase such information from our records.  We recommend that minors over the age of 13 ask their parents for permission before sending any information about themselves to anyone over the Internet, and we urge parents to instruct their children to never give out their real names, addresses or phone numbers, without permission, when using the Internet.

If for any reason you are concerned that your child's personal information maintained by us is not correct or complete, you wish to have your child's personal information deleted from our records, or you want us to discontinue further collection or use of your child's personal information, please contact our Privacy Policy Administrator who will be happy to review, update or remove your child's information as appropriate.

**xiv.      How to Review and Correct Your Information**

If for any reason you are concerned that the personal information maintained by Glu is not correct, or should you wish to have your account(s) deactivated or be removed from our mailing list, please email the Privacy Policy Administrator. We will be happy to review, update or remove information as appropriate. We may still retain your information in our files, however, to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreement, and maintain the security, integrity and operation of the Sites and Services.

Users in certain jurisdictions have a right to access personal information held about themselves. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with applicable law. Please see “How to Contact Us” below to submit any requests for access to your personal data.

**xv.       How to Contact Us**

We welcome your questions and comments about privacy. Please send your feedback to our [Privacy Policy Administrator](mailto:privacy@glu.com) and any requests for access to your personal information in writing to privacy@glu.com.

Last Updated: May 21, 2012
